James Hennessey

Contact 41 Saint Davids Sq

Information London

e-mail: jameswhennessey@gmail.com website: jwhennessey.com github: github.com/JWHennessey

E14 3WA

RESEARCH INTERESTS

My research interests are computer graphics, computer vision, 3D fabrication and HCI. I'm currently working on two research projects. The first aims of to simplify the creation of 2D and 3D computer graphics for novice users. The second is to detect and prevent errors in 3D printers using a computer vision system.

EDUCATION

University College London

EngD Virtual Environments, Imaging and Visualisation

September 2013 - Current

Supervisors: Dr Niloy Mitra (1^{st}) and Professor Anthony Steed (2^{nd})

Research Group: Smart Geometry

University College London

Distinction MSc Computer Science

September 2011 – September 2012

Supervisor: Dr Niloy Mitra

Thesis: Statistical Human Body Shape Analysis and Prediction

University of Leeds

1st BA New Media

September 2008 – June 2011

Supervisor: Dr Helen Kennedy

Thesis: Social Media Monitoring and Sentiment Analysis

Honours and Awards

Peter Williams Prize

University College London

November 2012

The prize is awarded to the student with the best overall performance in the MSc Computer Science and MSc Financial Computing courses.

Enterprise Scholarship

University of Leeds

December 2010

The scholarship provided training and a small amount of capital to launch Social Insight Ltd.

Professional Experience

University College London, London

Postgraduate Teaching Assistant

January 2014 - Current

Teaching assistant for a masters Software Engineering module. My main responsibility is supervising group projects where students architect and implement a large software system.

University College London, London

Research Engineer

September 2013 - Current

I undertake industrial focused research as part of my Engineering Doctorate in Virtual Environments, Imaging and Visualisation. The doctorate includes taking advanced CS modules at UCL and MBA electives at the London Business School.

Code First Girls, London

Course Instructor

June 2013 - Current

To date I've taught two courses are part of the Code First: Girls programme. The courses teaches the basics of web programming (HTML, CSS, git, Ruby, Sinatra and Ruby on Rails) to selected female university students and recent-graduates.

uMotif, London

Freelance Software Engineer

January 2013 – September 2013

I lead development of uMotif's Popup Clinic project. This includes a native Android tablet app and companion website. I also assisted in the server-side development for their mobile healthcare apps.

Optim.io, London

Co-founder

September 2012 – January 2013

A company I co-founded after graduation as part of the Entrepreneur First graduate scheme. I lead development of a mobile app to help women with gestational diabetes manage their blood glucose and provide reports for their doctor.

University College London, London

Teaching Assistant

January 2012 - June 2012

Teaching assistant for the Information Services Department offering support during sessions teaching software such as UNIX, Matlab and Photoshop.

University of Leeds, Leeds

Teaching Assistant

January 2011 - July 2011

Teaching assistant for a second year module Creating Database Applications for the Web. The module teaches PHP and SQL.

Social Insight, Leeds

Founder

December 2010 - September 2011

I founded Social Insight a social media monitoring and sentiment analysis company while still a student. I raised a small amount of capital for the company through the university Enterprise Scholarship.

Unruly Media, London

Operations Executive

July 2010 - January 2011

Summer intern and later a freelancer in Unruly's operations team when the company was <20 employees. I was responsible for building relationships with publishers and providing reporting to clients.